A Finding Aid to the Howard Kanovitz papers, 1953-2017, bulk 1963-1999, in the Archives of American Art.
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1960-2017; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 1.95 Linear feet Box 4-5, 8; OV 14
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1980, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1988-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1990-1992, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Event Programs, 1985-1993, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Everyman Gallery, Catalog, Typography, and Photographs, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Germany - A State of Flux" by Dieter Wellershoff, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - German Press Clipings, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hedendaagse Kunst-Utrecht Exhibition Catalog and Announcements, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Howard Kanovitz Retrospective Catalogs and Installation Photographs, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Magazines, 1966-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Magazines, 1973-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Posters, circa 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 14)
  - Reviews, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Reviews, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Reviews, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Reviews, 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Reviews, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Reviews, 1982-1983, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Reviews, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Reviews, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Reviews, 2002-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Reviews, Alex Rosenberg Gallery, 1982, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Semi-Colon Poetry Newsletter, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Serpentine Gallery Catalog and Clippings, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Stable Gallery Reviews, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Wadell Gallery Exhibition Announcements, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Works on Paper Exhibition Scrap Book of Digital Prints, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Artwork, circa 1960s-circa 1990s; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Box 5, 8, 10; OV 11-13; OV 15-18
  Artwork includes large-scale preparatory drawings for Kanovitz's photo-based paintings, as well as sketchbooks and smaller studies from the 1960s to 1990s. Materials include a collage, sketchbooks, loose sketches, oversize sketches, photographic and paper-based source material, and set design model pieces. Projects include "Hampton Drive-In," "New Yorker I" and "New Yorker II," "Supermarket Charter," and Weinstin's circa 1977 play, "The Party." "The Party" includes set design sketches, photographs, and model pieces.
  - Collage, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Sketchbook, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Sketchbook, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Sketches, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Sketches, undated; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 12)
  - Sketches, undated; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 18)
  - Sketches and Photographs, circa 1964, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Sketches and Thumbnail Prints, circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sketches and Thumbnail Prints, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sketches, Hampton's Drive-In, undated; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 15)
  - Sketches, New Yorker I and II, undated; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 13)
  - Sketches, Prints, undated; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 16)
  - Sketches, Supermarket Charter, undated; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 17)
  - Source Material, 1968, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Source Material, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Source Material, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Source Material, New York II Mike Stollen Collection, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Weinstein's "The Party" Set Design Model Piece [1 of 3], circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Item 1)
  - Weinstein's "The Party" Set Design Model Piece [2 of 3], circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Item 2)
  - Weinstein's "The Party" Set Design Model Piece [3 of 3], circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Item 3)
  - Weinstein's "The Party" Set Design Sketches and Photographs, circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 11)
- Photographic Material, 1954-2008; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 1.4 Linear feet Box 6-7
  Photographic material documents Kanovitz's friendships; projects, including a 1969 Sports Illustrated campaign; artwork; installations; Kanovitz's studio; studies and source material for artworks from 1954 to 2008. Included are color and black and white prints, polaroids, negatives, transparencies, contact sheets, digital prints, and slides, which make up the bulk of the series. People of note include Larry Rivers, Frank O'Hara, and Ph Segura.
  - 4 A.M. Eastern Standard Time Negatives, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Alex Rosenberg Gallery Installation Views, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Black and White Prints, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Black and White Prints, 1971-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Black and White Prints, Lunch, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bruno Taut - Buildings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Collector's Wall, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Death in Treme, Source Material, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Digital Prints, 1967-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Dokumentas Installation Photographs, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Early Laser Print, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Famille Gris, circa 1997-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - George Grosz, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Hampton Drive-In, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Howard Kanovitz's Studio, circa 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Jersey Tower Studies, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Max and Joe (and Thom), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - New Yorkers, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Paintings, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Paintings, Early 1960s, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Ph Segura Print Signed by the Artist, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Photographs of Kanovitz and Friends, 1956-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Photographs of Kanovitz and Friends, 1988-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Photographs of Kanovitz and Friends, 1988-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Polaroids and Prints, 1970-1986, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Polaroids of Artwork, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Prints and Negatives of Rooming House Door, Smithtown Project Model, and Furniture, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Slides, Artwork, 1967-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Slides, Artwork, 1968-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Slides, Balls and Objects, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Slides, Berlin, Waechter Apartment, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Slides, Bruno Taut Architecture, George Grosz, Waechter, Marlene Dietrich, Albert Einstein, Tucholsky, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Slides, Chairs and Lights, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Slides, Cologne, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Slides, Cuba, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Slides, Current Studies: New Painting, Door Shadows, Dead Flowers, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Slides, Die Bakchen - Drawings and Models, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Slides, Diagonal Sunlight on Broome Street Wall - Berlin Windows, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Slides Friends: Rainer Grosz, Michael Florescu, Courtney Bean, Jorn Merkert, Gold and Fizdale, Dorothy Beskin, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Slides, Gardeners' Bay Entry, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Slides, Helen R. House - New Shots, Window, Chair, Sconce, etc., 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Slides, Hokin - Kaufman Gallery Installation Images, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Slides, Howard at Arts Litho Paris - March of '74, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Slides, Howard, CNAC, Paris, Hyper Realist Exhibit - April 1974, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Slides, Installation Views, circa 1980s-circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Slides, Kurt Weil, Maxsolmelling, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Slides, Larry R[ivers]'s Party for Earl McGrath: Jan '94 - Minolta Flasa, Ulli, Judith, H.K. Rainer, Anselma, Arnold, Camilla, Kate, etc., 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Slides, Leo's Gift, The Print, Time Magazine, Composition, Living Room, Destroyed Painting, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Slides, Lia and F. Tuten at L. Jokel Party, Lia at F[rank]. O'Hara Grave, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Slides, Men's Suit Dummy, South Ferry Subway, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Slides, Minolta Zoom Test, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Slides, New Cannon Elan - First Test Shots, Decebmer '92, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Slides, New Skies - Amagansett and Skies for "Way to London" and "Red Sky in the Morning", 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Slides, Paris, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Slides, Party at Susan and Debbie's: Watermill 8/93, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Slides, Photographs of Birds, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Slides, Photographs of Design Studio, 1998-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Slides, Photographs of the Sea and Sky, 1987-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Slides, Photographs of Trees, 1983-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Slides, Prague - Jewish Cemetery and Other, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Slides, S. Rivers Barmitzvah - Carolyn H.K., Heidi, Erin, Larry, etc., 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Slides, Steven Lion, Larry R[ivers]., Dorothy Beskin, Ellen Adler, Sarah Opp., Lukas Foss, Ulli Gering, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Slides, Studio and Apartment - Nikon 8008, Jan. '89, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Slides, the Painting Wall and Water Bucket Stool, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Slides, Vienna, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Sports Illustrated [1], 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Sports Illustrated [2], 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Stable Gallery, Installation Views, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Studies for 1980 - Pastels, 1980-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Studies: Grand Piano, Terasse Paintings, Atlantis (Yellow Plane), Sleeping Dog, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "The Actors," 1965 Original, Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - The People Multiple, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - The Wall, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Twelve Parts of Rain," Digital Print, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Waddell Show, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Sound Recordings and Video Recordings, 1967-2008; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Box 7, 9
  Conditions Governing Access
  Archival audiovisual recordings must be digitized for research access. Researchers may access digitized audiovisual materials in the Archives' Washington, D.C. or New York, N.Y. Research Centers by appointment.
  Sound recordings and video recordings include sound recordings of Charles Simic reading poetry in the Village in 1990; a circa 1990s lecture given by Howard Kanovitz; BBC featuring Kanovitz's friend, Peter Lennon; an interview A. Post used for a 1982 paper regarding Kanovitz; and commercial sound recordings of "Modern American Poets" and Jamey Aebersold Play-A-Long, "All Time Standards." Video recordings include the opera, "Ariadne Auf Naxos;" the 2007 film,"Camera and Mirror: Howard Kanovitz Painting Through the Lens," the 2008 film, "Hotel Le Provencal;" the 1967 and 2007 films narrated by Peter Lennon, "Rocky Road to Dublin;" Kanovitz in his Amagansett studio; a 1988 Marlborough Gallery show; the Marlene Dietrich documentary, "The Blue Angel;" and a 1992 Miss Fitness U.S.A. competition.
  - A. Post Paper Re Howard Kanovitz, 1982; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound cassettes (microcassette) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Ariadne Auf Naxos, Richard Strauss, Semperoper Dresden, Set with the Opening, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Item 1)
  - BBC Broadcasts Featuring Peter Lennon, 1998; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Erin Amerikaner in Mulheim, Kanowitz [sic] malt fur Ciulli, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Item 2)
  - Film, "Camera and Mirror: Howard Kanovitz Painting Through the Lens", 2007; Archival Resource Key; 1 Electronic discs (DVD) (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Film, "Hotel Le Provencal", 2008; Archival Resource Key; 1 Electronic discs (CD); 1 Electronic discs (DVD) (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Film, "Rocky Road to Dublin" Narrated by Peter Lennon, 1967, 2006; Archival Resource Key; 2 Electronic discs (DVD) (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Howard Kanovitz in His Studio - Amagansett, 1992; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 9, Item 3)
  - Howard Kanovitz Lecture, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Jamey Aebersold Play-A-Long, "All Time Standards", undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Marlborough Show, 1988; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Item 4)
  - Marlene Dietrich Documentary, "The Blue Angel", undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Item 5)
  - Miss Fitness U.S.A., 1992; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Item 6)
  - Modern American Poets, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Item 7)
  - Poets Reading in the Village: Charles Simic, 1990; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Digital Sound Recordings and Photographs, circa 2005-circa 2007; Archival Resource Key; 2 USB flash drive (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Digital Sound and Video Recordings, circa 1985-circa 2008; Archival Resource Key; 4 Sound discs (CD); 2 Electronic discs (DVD) (Box 7, Folder 29)